Finding Aid for Board of Regents (University of Michigan) Records 1817-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical File
  - Ca, 1958-2006
    - Bylaws (Box 179)
      - Regents' Bylaws 1983-revisions (Box 180)
      - Regents' Bylaws Revisions, 1984 (Box 180)
      - Regents' Bylaws Revisions, 1985 (Box 180)
      - Regents' Bylaws, 1986 (Box 180)
      - Regents' Bylaws, 1988 (Box 180)
    - Parking Ordinance Revisions, 1991-1995 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Aftermath, 1975-1992 (Box 181)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence-Regent Emeritus, 1968-1999 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Newspaper Articles, 1990-1998 (Box 181)
    - Executive Sessions, 1977-1999 (Box 181)
    - Detroit Free Press Regents' Expense Report, 1989-1990 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Expenses Detroit News, 1987-1988 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Expenses, 1975-1992 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Proceedings, 1961-1985 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat, 1982-1985 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Hidden Valley Retreat, 1977 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Hidden Valley, 1976 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Hidden Valley, 1975 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Hidden Valley, 1974 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Hidden Valley, 1973 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Boyne Highlands, 1972 (Box 181)
    - Regents' Retreat Hidden Valley, 1971 (Box 181)
    - Another Problem in Flint (Box 181)
    - Financial and Operational Challenges Presentation by Geoffrey Shields, 1996 (Box 181)
    - Medical Center Issue Presentation, 1995 (Box 181)
    - "A Thoughtful Discussion of Political Correctness and American Values,", 1993 (Box 181)
    - "Strategic Planning Overview," University Housing, 1997 (Box 181)
    - Alcohol and Other Drugs, 1993 (Box 181)
- Correspondence Files
  The Correspondence, 1959-1973 series consists of alphabetically an chronologically organized files relating to gifts to the university and general university business.
  - Regents' Correspondence (alphabetical), 1961-1973
    - A-B (Box 68)
    - C (Box 68)
    - D-H (Box 68)
    - K-L (I and J lacking) (Box 68)
    - M-O (Box 68)
    - P-S (Box 68)
    - T-Z (Box 68)
  - Regents' Correspondence, Chronological, 1963-1973
    - 1963-1966 (Box 68)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 68)
    - 1969 (Box 68)
    - 1970, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - 1971 (Box 68)
    - 1972 (Box 68)
    - Crank letters, 1959-1973 (scattered dates) (Box 68)
  - Regents' Correspondence (chronological), 1966-1970
    - Gift Letters
      - (alphabetical), 1966 (Box 106)
        - A-L, 3 folders (Box 106)
        - M-Z, 2 folders (Box 106)
      - 1967
        - A-G, 3 folders (Box 106)
        - H-O, 3 folders (Box 106)
        - P-Z, 3 folders (Box 106)
      - 1968
        - A-L, 3 folders (Box 107)
        - M-Z, 3 folders (Box 107)
      - 1969, 2 folders (Box 107)
      - (bound), 1970 (Box 107)
      - (bound), 1972-1973 (Box 107)
    - Miscellaneous Regents' Correspondence
      - 1969
        - January (Box 107)
        - February (Box 107)
        - June (Box 107)
        - July (Box 107)
        - September (Box 107)
        - October (Box 107)
        - November (Box 107)
        - December (Box 107)
      - 1970
        - January (Box 107)
        - February (Box 107)
        - March (Box 107)
        - April (Box 107)
        - May (Box 107)
        - June (Box 107)
- Recordings of the Regents Meetings (audio cassettes)
  The series Recordings of the Regents Meetings contains audio recordings of the Board of Regents meetings, primarily audio cassette tapes of Regents' meetings from 1977 to 2011. One reel-to-reel recording from a 1973 meeting is also included.
  - September 21, 1973, 2 audiotapes 7-inch; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 109)
  - May 1977-October 1978 (Box 69)
  - November 1978-March 1980 (Box 70)
  - April 1980-October 1981 (Box 71)
  - November 1981-April 1983 (Box 72)
  - May 1983-March 1985 (Box 73a)
  - April 1985-May 1987 (Box 73b)
  - June 1987-December 1987, 1 audiocassettes (Box 109)
  - January 1988-May 1988 (Box 119)
  - March 1988-April 1988, 4 audiocassettes (Box 109)
  - June 1988-December 1992 (Box 120)
  - October 1991, 1 audiocassettes (Box 109)
  - January 1993-May 1997, 180 audiocassettes (Box 151)
  - June 1997-December 2002, 180 audiocassettes (Box 152)
  - January 2003-December 2004, 36 audiocassettes (Box 161)
  - February 2005-July 2011, 111 audiocassettes approximate (Box 173)
  - Undated, 4 audiocassettes (Box 109)
  - Undated, held in Union Ballroom, 1 audiotapes 7-inch; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 109)
- Presidential Search Records
  The Presidential Search series documents the hiring of university presidents in 1988 and 1996/ The records include including detailed files on the final candidates, with transcriptions of their interviews and town meeting sessions; minutes of presidential search committee and presidential search advisory committee meetings; and feedback from various constituencies through forums held throughout the state. Records relating to some earlier presidential searches can be found in the Topical Files series.
  - 1988
    - Candidates' Biographical Data, 5 folders
      - A-C (Box 110)
      - D-I (Box 110)
      - J-P (Box 110)
      - R-T (Box 110)
      - U-Z (Box 111)
    - Budget and Expenses of Search (Box 111)
    - Chronology of Presidential Search Events (Box 111)
    - Faculty Advisory Committee Materials (unmarked green notebook, includes Preliminary Minutes) (Box 111)
    - Faculty Advisory Committee Final Minutes, September 15, 1987-May 24, 1988 (Box 111)
    - Freedom of Information Requests and Litigation (Box 111)
    - Kauper File (Materials of Professor Thomas Kauper, chair of Faculty Advisory Committee for the Presidential Search) (Box 111)
    - Nellie Varner's Copy of Memorandum from Thomas Kauper to Presidential Search Committee, November 4, 1987 (Box 111)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 111)
    - "Presidential Selection Committee, 1966", 2 volumes (Box 111)
    - "Presidential Selection Committee, 1978" (Box 111)
    - Selection Committees Information and Statements (notebook is entitled "Presidential Selection Committee, Faculty Advisory Committee, Student Advisory Committee, Alumni Advisory Committee") (Box 111)
  - 1995-1996
    - Board of Regents Special Meeting (Box 141)
      - October 12, 1996, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 142)
      - November 12, 1995, Audiocassette (Box 142)
    - Final Candidates
      - Lee Bollinger
        - Board of Regents' Interview, October 24, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
        - First News Conference as President, November 12, 1996
          - Audio and Video (Box 142)
        - Town Meeting, October 24, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
      - Stanley Chodorow
        - Background, 2 folders (Box 141)
        - Board of Regents' Interview, October 22, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
        - Correspondence (Box 141)
        - Town Meeting, October 22, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
      - Carol Christ
        - Background (Box 141)
        - Board of Regents' Interview, October 21, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
        - Correspondence (Box 141)
        - Town Meeting, October 21, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
      - Finalists Named, Video (housed in Box 142), October 18, 1996 (Box 141)
      - Larry Faulkner
        - Background (Box 141)
        - Board of Regents' Interview, October 28, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
        - Correspondence (Box 141)
        - Town Meeting, October 28, 1996
          - Transcription (Box 141)
          - Video (Box 142)
    - Freedom of Information Requests and Responses (Box 141)
    - Information Packet for Candidates (Box 141)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2 folders (Box 141)
    - Presidential Search Advisory Committee
      - Charge and Membership (Box 141)
      - Correspondence (Box 141)
      - Reports to Regents (Box 141)
    - Presidential Search Committee (Box 142)
    - Audio Recordings 21 cassettes
      - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 141)
      - Meeting Minutes, 4 folders (Box 141)
      - Video Recordings, 3 video recordings (Box 142)
    - Proposed Timeline (Box 141)
    - Presidential Search Forums
      - Analysis of Comments (Box 142)
      - Audio Recordings, 11 audiocassettes (Box 142)
      - Computer Disks, 6 floppy disks (Box 142)
      - Transcriptions
        - Alumni, December 14, 1995 (Box 142)
        - Detroit, January 17, 1996 (Box 142)
        - Faculty, December 4, 1995 (Box 142)
        - Ford Library, January 19, 1996 (Box 142)
        - Grand Rapids, January 10, 1996 (Box 142)
        - Staff, December 14, 1995 (Box 142)
        - Students, December 4, 1995 (Box 142)
        - U-M Dearborn, January 18, 1996 (Box 142)
        - U-M Flint, January 18, 1996 (Box 142)
    - Presidential Selection Criteria (Box 142)
    - Student Input (Box 142)
    - Chronology and Process (Box 142)
    - Towers Perrin Invoice (Box 142)
    - Visual/Audio Materials
      - Audio Materials
        - Board of Regents Special Meeting, November 12, 1996 (Box 142)
        - President Lee Bollinger's First News Conference, November 12, 1996 (Box 142)
        - Presidential Search Committee Meetings, 21 audiocassettes (Box 142)
        - Presidential Search Forum, 11 audiocassettes (Box 142)
      - Video Materials
        - Board of Regents Special Meeting, October 12, 1996; VHS (Box 142)
        - Final Candidates
          - Lee Bollinger
            - Board of Regents' Interview (Box 142)
            - News Conference (Box 142)
            - Town Hall Meeting (Box 142)
          - Stanley Chodorow
            - Board of Regents' Interview, VHS (Box 142)
            - Town Hall Meeting (Box 142)
          - Carol Christ
            - Board of Regents' Interview, VHS (Box 142)
            - Town Hall Meeting, VHS (Box 142)
          - Committee Names Finalists, VHS (Box 142)
          - Larry Faulkner
            - Board of Regents' Interview, VHS (Box 142)
            - Town Hall Meeting, VHS (Box 142)
      - Presidential Search Committee Meetings (Box 142)
        - October 17, 1996, VHS (Box 142)
        - November 5, 1996, VHS (Box 142)
          (2 tapes)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials consists a small collection of photographs, primarily related to the university's flags, and some group and individual photos of regents ca. 1966-1973 including a set of portraits by Csaba Martonyi, Additional portraits of regents can be found in the separate collections U-M Board of Regents Portrait Collection and in the papers of individual regents.)
  (see also U-M Board of Regents Portrait Collection)
  - Campus view, print and negatives (Box 92)
  - Commencements, black & white prints (Box 92)
  - Gores, Walter J. (Box 92)
    (see also Box 67)
  - Regents' meetings (Box 92)
  - Regents in Ceremonial Robes, June 1962; black & white print (Box 92)
  - Regents' meeting (University of Michigan Hospital, Office of Planning, research & development), March 17, 1977; color print (Box 92)
  - Regents' portraits (Box 92)
  - Sarah Goddard Power's Pictures, black & white prints (Box 92)
  - University of Michigan Flags
    - Black & white prints (Box 92)
    - Color prints (Box 92)
    - Color transparencies (Box 92)
    - Color transparencies (Box 92)
      (use copy)
    - Negatives of transparencies (Box 92)
    - Sketches and color samples (Box 92)
    - Color slides, 2 copies (Box 92)
  - Group and Individual Photographs of the Regents, 1993-1997 (Box 92)
  - Group Photo of Regents and President Bollinger, 1997 (Box 92)
  - Copies of images used in Board of Regents Bulletin, 1996 (Box 92)
  - Portraits by Csaba Martonyi, circa 1970-1973
    - Deane Baker (Box 174)
    - Paul W. Brown (Box 174)
    - William B. Cudlip (Box 174)
    - Gerald R. Dunn (Box 174)
    - Paul G. Goebel (Box 174)
    - Gertrude V. Huebner (Box 174)
    - Lawrence B. Lindemer (Box 174)
    - Robert E. Nederlander (Box 174)
    - Regents Square (Box 174)
    - Otis M. Smith (Box 174)
    - James L. Waters (Box 174)
    - Unidentified (Box 174)
    - Regents' Final Negatives (Box 174)
- Archived Website
  The Archived Website series (296.6 MB, 2005, 2006; 2010- ) documents the mission, activities, policies, and individuals involved with the Board of Regents as presented on its public website. Content includes publications (such as reports and administrative documents) and information about meetings, initiatives, and governance. The series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1996 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists in 2005 and 2006. Starting in 2010, this archived website has been captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/
  - Board of Regents
    - 1996-2006
      (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - October 28, 2005, .ZIP file
    - 2006-[ONGOING]
    - December 7, 2006, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ONGOING]
Related Material
More recent materials from the Regents meetings (from March 1996 to present), including detailed agendas, exhibit material, and reports on finances, promotions, and degree confirmation, are available in the record group University of Michigan. Board of Regents Agendas.
The Bentley holds a number of archival records, manuscript collection, and publications relating to the Board of Regents, including the published minutes (proceedings) of the Board; personal papers of board members, university presidents, and other university officials; the records of many university offices, including the Presidents Office and the University Secretary.
Both the index and the full text of the Board of Regents Proceedings are available online. The Index to the Regent's Proceedings is available through the Board of Regents' web site at http://www.umich.edu/~regents/regntweb.htm. The searchable, full-text version of the Regents' Proceedings is provided by the Digital Library Production Service at http://www.hti.umich.edu/u/umregproc/
A complete list of members of the Board of Regents is available online at http://www.umich.edu/~bhl/bhl/exhibits/regents/regenttp.htm.